<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<node id="ResourceTypeGenres" label="SRL 2020-01-16">
  <isComposedBy>
    <node id="ID1" label="SRL 1 - scientific research results show the basic functional principles and relationships. No statements can be made about the transferability to a field of application.">
    <hasNote>Examples:
- Basic research
- Results were obtained in the laboratory or other highly controlled environment
- Development of hypotheses or theoretical concepts (desk research)</hasNote>
    </node>
    <node id="ID2" label="SRL 2 -  Problem and application relevance of the results were established theoretically (inner-scientific concept development)

">
    <hasNote>Examples: 
- a relationship between research results and a possible application is soundly argued. 
- Results from different disciplines were identified for a problem solution 
- Requirements, development needs, restrictions etc. for an application were specified  
- Relevant stakeholders were identified for further work on problem solving
- first tests show the problem-solving capacity of the basic functional principles
- application-oriented research results are available from a context that is very different from the intended field of application. The possible transferability into the intended field of application was worked out theoretically.</hasNote>
    </node>
    <node id="ID3" label="SRL 3 - Problem and application relevance have been demonstrated in small experiments or studies and/or were designed through participative processes with relevant actors groups">
    <hasNote>Examples:
- Tests/research takes place with reference to the real application environment 
- Results confirm a 'proof of concept' in the application environment
- Important partial components of the solution approach were designed
- Joint project was carried out with extensive participation of practice
- Reflection with relevant stakeholders on problem description, solution approach and/or requirements of the application environment has taken place
- Know-how from practice was integrated 
- Stakeholders consider the possible applications to be realistic</hasNote>
    </node>
    <node id="ID4" label="SRL 4 - Tests close to reality prove the applicability and the solution potential. Obstacles/deficits regarding the applicability can be described. A further development seems promising. ">
    <hasNote>Examples: 
- transdisciplinary research and development, practice-oriented experiments and/or the integration of know-how from practice show a robust solution potential
- prototypical development of solutions for subsystems has taken place
- prototypical development of individual solution components has taken place
- Interfaces between solution components are defined
- the further development needs can be specified on the basis of the results, further development seems promising  

</hasNote>
    </node>
    <node id="ID5" label="SRL 5 - A further development could eliminate identified obstacles/deficits regarding the applicability. Eventually, this has already been demonstrated by a re-test.">
    <hasNote>- some solution components were optimised
- problems encountered in the test have been resolved
- Application obstacles have been successfully addressed
- specific requirements from the application field were integrated
- Solution approach was further developed with the involvement of various groups of actors and controversial views
- Functionality of the improved prototypical solution components was proven
- Interest of stakeholders in an application exists
</hasNote>
    </node>
    <node id="ID6" label="SRL 6 - exemplary application/testing in a specific field of application within the project or by external actors">
    <hasNote>Exemplary = conditions close to reality, but still idealized Exemplary = conditions close to reality, but still idealized (e.g. no complete economic efficiency required, financial support is provided, special voluntary, idealistic or material support, exemptions are granted)

Examples:
- Demonstrators/prototypes were developed for a specific application environment (e.g. specific region, framework conditions, group of actors)
- Combination of different solution components to a complete solution has been achieved
- Solution approach is tested in a specific field of application (e.g. in everyday practices of a specific group of actors)
- Model project in a certain region is carried out 
- Pre-commercial stage of a production process was implemented (pilot operation)
</hasNote>
    </node>
    <node id="ID7" label="SRL 7 - Manifold model application/testing in different fields of application.">
    <hasNote>Exemplary = conditions close to reality, but still idealized Exemplary = conditions close to reality, but still idealized (e.g. no complete economic efficiency required, financial support is provided, special voluntary, idealistic or material support, exemptions are granted)

Examples:
As for SRL 6, but there are various model applications, e.g:
- in different reasons
- under different conditions (e.g. ecological, economic, social/cultural) 
- Implementation by or with extensive participation of different groups of actors external to the project
- adapted for different problem situations or contexts</hasNote>
    </node>
    <node id="ID8" label="SRL 8 - First application or pilot operation under completely realistic conditions. ">
    <hasNote>Examples:
- the solution is complete, functional and commercially viable
- the solution is used or tested in everyday practice under complete application-specific restrictions 
- External actors apply the solution or transfer the solution to other contexts
- the solution/application works, but the environment is not yet fully prepared for widespread use</hasNote>
    </node>
    <node id="ID9" label="SRL 9 - Proven applications and suitable framework conditions show the suitability for widespread use.">
    <hasNote>Examples:
- the solution has proven its suitability for everyday use and functionality
- the framework conditions are also in place for a widespread application</hasNote>
    </node>
  </isComposedBy>
</node>
