<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<node id="ResourceTypeGenres" label="APPLICABILITY-SOCIAL 2020-01-16">
  <isComposedBy>
    <node id="APLS1" label="Requirements for application at stakeholder level">
    <hasNote>Which key stakeholders should definitely be involved? Which elementary conflicting goals between stakeholders should be taken into account? What specific skills and knowledge are required by the involved actors to apply the solution? Does the innovation rely on voluntary commitment or is personnel needed?</hasNote>
    </node>
    <node id="APLS2" label="Requirements for application regarding (infra)structures and Ressoucen">
    <hasNote>What infrastructure, equipment, materials etc. are required to implement the solution? What effort is involved in implementing the solution? Which institutional links, organisational structures and agreements have proved to be helpful? </hasNote>
    </node>
    <node id="APLS3" label="Prospects for a continued establishment  of the social innovation (at the location of implementation)">
    <hasNote>Has the integration of the key stakeholders been successful? Was it possible to establish a continuous collaboration? Was it possible to reach a consensus among stakeholders? Are there enough qualified actors available (volunteers or staff)? Has networking with and visibility among the population been achieved? Are there financing possibilities for a continuation? Is the innovation politically supported? Have viable structures been created? (e.g. organisational structures, institutional links, agreements, facilities etc.) </hasNote>
    </node>
    <node id="APLS4" label="Prospects for transmission and diffusion">
    <hasNote>To what extent is the solution transferable (to other sectors, regions, user groups etc.)?  Whether and how must structures and framework conditions be changed to allow a diffusion of the solution? Which supporting structures and framework conditions already exist that promote the establishment / transfer / spread of the solution?  Are there financing possibilities to support a broader establishment? Does the solution touch on conflicting interests that threaten its establishment?</hasNote>
    </node>
  </isComposedBy>
</node>
