<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<node id="ResourceTypeGenres" label="BUSINESS-INNOVATION 2019-11-08">
  <isComposedBy>
    <node id="ID01" label="Product innovation">
    <hasNote>Product  innovations  must  provide  significant  improvements  to  one  or  more characteristics or performance specifications. This includes the addition of new functions,or improvements to  existing  functions  or  user  utility.  Relevant  functional  characteristics include quality, technical specifications, reliability, durability, economic efficiency during use, affordability, convenience, usability, and user friendliness. Goods and services include knowledge-capturing products, and combinations thereof. Includes the design characteristics of goods and services. (OECD 2018 - Oslo Manual)</hasNote>
      <isComposedBy>
        <node id="ID02" label="Goods">
        <hasNote>Goods include  tangible  objects  and  some  knowledge-capturing  products over which ownership rights can be established and whose ownership can be transferred through market transactions. (OECD 2018 - Oslo Manual)</hasNote>
          <isComposedBy>
            <node id="ID03" label="Knowledge-capturing products">
            <hasNote>Knowledge-capturing products concern the provision,
storage, communication and dissemination of information,
advice and entertainment in such a way that the consuming
unit can access the knowledge repeatedly. (SNE 2008 refered to in OECD 2018 - Oslo Manual)</hasNote>
            </node>
          </isComposedBy>
        </node>
        <node id="ID04" label="Service ">
        <hasNote>Services are intangible activities that are produced and consumed simultaneously and  that  change  the  conditions  (e.g.physical,  psychological,  etc.)  of  users. (OECD 2018 - Oslo Manual)</hasNote>
          <isComposedBy>
            <node id="ID05" label="Knowledge-capturing products">
            <hasNote>Knowledge-capturing products concern the provision,
storage, communication and dissemination of information,
advice and entertainment in such a way that the consuming
unit can access the knowledge repeatedly. (SNE 2008 refered to in OECD 2018 - Oslo Manual)</hasNote>
            </node>
          </isComposedBy>
        </node>
        <node id="ID06" label="Combination of goods and service">
        <hasNote>The dividing line between goods and services can sometimes
be difficult to establish and some products can have characteristics of both. A company can
sell goods to its customers or rent their use as a service, as is often the case for durable
consumer goods and for assets for business production. (OECD 2018 - Oslo Manual)</hasNote>
          <isComposedBy>
            <node id="ID07" label="Knowledge-capturing products">
            <hasNote>Knowledge-capturing products concern the provision,
storage, communication and dissemination of information,
advice and entertainment in such a way that the consuming
unit can access the knowledge repeatedly. (SNE 2008 refered to in OECD 2018 - Oslo Manual)</hasNote>
            </node>
          </isComposedBy>
        </node>
      </isComposedBy>
        </node>
    <node id="ID08" label="Business process innovation">
    <hasNote>A business process innovationis a new or improved business process for one or more business functions that differs significantly from the firm’s previous business processes and that has been brought into use in the firm. (OECD 2018 - Oslo Manual)</hasNote>
      <isComposedBy>
        <node id="ID09" label="Production of goods or services">
        <hasNote>Activities that transform inputs into goods or services, including engineering and related technical testing, analysis and certification activities to support production. (OECD 2018 - Oslo Manual)</hasNote>
        </node>
        <node id="ID10" label="Distribution and logistics">
        <hasNote>This function includes: a) transportationand service delivery b) warehousing c) order processing. (OECD 2018 - Oslo Manual)</hasNote>
        </node>
        <node id="ID11" label="Marketing and sales">
        <hasNote>This function includes: a) marketingmethods including advertising (product promotion and placement, packaging of products), direct marketing (telemarketing), exhibitions and fairs, market research and other activities to develop new markets b) pricing strategies and methods c) sales and after-sales activities, including helpdesks other customer support and customer relationship activities. (OECD 2018 - Oslo Manual)</hasNote>
        </node>
        <node id="ID12" label="Information and communication systems">
        <hasNote>The maintenance and provision of information and communication systems, including:a) hardwareand software b) data processing and database c) maintenance and repair d) web-hosting and other computer-related information activities. These functions can be provided in a separate division or in divisions responsible for other functions. (OECD 2018 - Oslo Manual)</hasNote>
        </node>
        <node id="ID13" label="Administration and management">
        <hasNote>This function includes: a) strategicand general business management (cross-functional decision-making), including organising work responsibilitiesb) corporate governance (legal, planning and public relations)c) accounting, bookkeeping, auditing, payments and other financial or insurance activities d) human resources management (training and education, staff recruitment, workplace organisation, provision of temporary personnel, payroll management, health and medical support)e) procurement f) managing external relationships with suppliers, alliances, etc. (OECD 2018 - Oslo Manual)</hasNote>
        </node>
        <node id="ID14" label="Product and business process development">
        <hasNote>Activities to scope, identify, develop, or adapt products or a firm's business processes. This function can be undertaken in a systematic fashion or on an adhoc basis, and be conducted within the firm or obtained from external sources. Responsibility for these activities can lie within a separate division or in divisions responsible for other functions, e.g.production of goods or services. Examples  of innovations in this function include the use of new gene editing technologies  to develop either existing or new plant varieties or pharmaceuticals and the application of data mining analysis to large databases to identify potential market development opportunities. Other examples  for  an  innovation in  this  category include  the  adoption  of  new  methodologiessuch as design thinking, co-creation, rapid prototyping or high-throughput screening. (OECD 2018 - Oslo Manual)</hasNote>
        </node>
      </isComposedBy>
    </node>
    <node id="ID15" label="Standards / norms / guidelines">
    <hasNote>Standards, norms and guidelines, that shape a certain field of business. Laws and regulations are assessed in the section social innovation and change.</hasNote>
    </node>
    <node id="ID16" label="Others (in the area of business innovation)">
    <hasNote>If existing types does not fit, choose "others"</hasNote>
    </node>
  </isComposedBy>
</node>
