<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<node id="ResourceTypeGenres" label="">
  <isComposedBy>
    <node id="c_3e5aa" label="contribution to journal" selectable="false">
    <hasNote></hasNote>
      <isComposedBy>
        <node id="c_6501" label="journal article" selectable="true">
        <hasNote>An article published in a scientific journal issue</hasNote>
        </node>
        <node id="c_3e5a" label="non-academic article" selectable="true">
        <hasNote>news item appearing in a general news periodical, containing information of current and timely interest in a field</hasNote>
        </node>
        <node id="c_998f" label="newspaper article" selectable="true">
        <hasNote>news item appearing in a general-interest newspaper</hasNote>
        </node>
      </isComposedBy>
    </node>
    <node id="c_93fc" label="report" selectable="false">
    <hasNote></hasNote>
      <isComposedBy>
        <node id="c_18hj" label="report to funding agency" selectable="true">
        <hasNote>Final report to a funding agency, written by beneficiaries of project grants. The report documents the scientific and technical work of a project</hasNote>
        </node>
        <node id="c_186u" label="policy report" selectable="true">
        <hasNote>Provides an in-depth look at major policy developments and events</hasNote>
        </node>
        <node id="c_18gh" label="technical report" selectable="true">
        <hasNote>Records the procedure adopted and results obtained from a scientific or technical activity or investigation</hasNote>
        </node>
        <node id="c_18wq" label="other type of report" selectable="true">
        <hasNote>Other types of report may include Business Plans Technical Specifications, data management plans, recommendation reports, white papers, annual reports, auditor's reports, workplace reports, census reports, trip reports, progress reports, investigative reports, budget reports, policy reports, demographic reports, credit reports, appraisal reports, inspection reports, military reports, bound reports, etc.</hasNote>
        </node>
      </isComposedBy>
    </node>
    <node id="c_5794" label="conference paper" selectable="true">
    <hasNote>A conference paper that is submitted to a conference and presented to the audience. The conference paper is published in proceedings.</hasNote>
    </node>
    <node id="c_3248" label="book part / part of monographic series" selectable="true">
    <hasNote>A defined chapter or section of a book, usually with a separate title or number.</hasNote>
    </node>
    <node id="c_ecc8" label="still image" selectable="true">
    <hasNote></hasNote>
    </node>
    <node id="c_8a7e" label="video" selectable="true">
    <hasNote></hasNote>
    </node>
    <node id="c_18cc" label="sound" selectable="true">
    <hasNote>A resource primarily intended to be heard. Examples include a music playback file format, an audio compact disc, and recorded speech or sounds.</hasNote>
    </node>
    <node id="c_18co" label="poster" selectable="true">
    <hasNote></hasNote>
    </node>
    <node id="c_46ec" label="thesis" selectable="false">
    <hasNote></hasNote>
      <isComposedBy>
        <node id="c_db06" label="doctoral thesis" selectable="true">
        <hasNote></hasNote>
        </node>
        <node id="c_bdcc" label="master thesis" selectable="true">
        <hasNote></hasNote>
        </node>
        <node id="c_7a1f" label="bachelor thesis" selectable="true">
        <hasNote></hasNote>
        </node>
      </isComposedBy>
    </node>
    <node id="c_5ce6" label="software" selectable="true">
    <hasNote>A computer program in source code (text) or compiled form.</hasNote>
    </node>
    <node id="c_7ad9" label="website" selectable="true">
    <hasNote></hasNote>
    </node>
    <node id="c_1843" label="Other types" selectable="false">
    <hasNote></hasNote>
      <isComposedBy>
        <node id="c_8042" label="working paper" selectable="true">
        <hasNote>An unpublished paper, usually circulated privately among a small group of peers, to provide information or with a request for comments or editorial improvement. (source: fabio)</hasNote>
        </node>
        <node id="c_6947" label="blog post" selectable="true">
        <hasNote>A piece of writing or other item of content published on a blog. (Adapted from oxforddictionaries)</hasNote>
        </node>
        <node id="c_86bc" label="bibliography" selectable="true">
        <hasNote>A systematic list or enumeration of written works by a specific author or on a given subject.</hasNote>
        </node>
        <node id="c_2f33" label="book / monographic series" selectable="true">
        <hasNote>A non-serial publication that is complete in one volume or a designated finite number of volumes. (adapted from CiTO; EPrint Type vocabulary)</hasNote>
        </node>
        <node id="c_71bd" label="manual" selectable="true">
        <hasNote></hasNote>
        </node>
        <node id="c_e059" label="learning object" selectable="true">
        <hasNote></hasNote>
        </node>
        <node id="c_816b" label="preprint" selectable="true">
        <hasNote>The first draft of an article - before peer-review, even before any contact with a publisher. This use is common amongst academics for whom the key modification of an article is the peer-review process. Another use of the term pre-print is for the finished article, reviewed and amended, ready and accepted for publication - but separate from the version that is type-set or formatted by the publisher. This use is more common amongst publishers, for whom the final and significant stage of modification to an article is the arrangement of the material for putting to print.</hasNote>
        </node>
        <node id="c_f744" label="conference proceedings" selectable="true">
        <hasNote>Conference proceedings is the official record of a conference meeting. It is a collection of documents which corresponds to the presentations given at the conference. It may include additional content.</hasNote>
        </node>
        <node id="c_0640" label="journal" selectable="true">
        <hasNote></hasNote>
        </node>
        <node id="c_2fe3" label="newspaper" selectable="true">
        <hasNote></hasNote>
        </node>
        <node id="c_8544" label="lecture" selectable="true">
        <hasNote>A transcription of a talk delivered during an academic event.</hasNote>
        </node>
        <node id="c_12cc" label="cartographic material" selectable="true">
        <hasNote>Any material representing the whole or part of the earth or any celestial body at any scale. Cartographic materials include two- and three-dimensional maps and plans (including maps of imaginary places); aeronautical, navigational, and celestial charts; atlases; globes; block diagrams; sections; aerial photographs with a cartographic purpose; bird's-eye views (map views), etc.</hasNote>
        </node>
        <node id="c_0050" label="others" selectable="true">
        <hasNote></hasNote>
        </node>
      </isComposedBy>
    </node>
  </isComposedBy>
</node>
